If I had a kickstarter campaign of 3.9 million dollars I would probably run. Obsidian got this chance
But they decided to create an enjoyable game with a classic feeling, like a bunch of morons
So two weeks ago, I pretty much promised an awful review of the first Assassin's Creed
Sadly I had a personal problem. The personal problem was called
Pillars of Eternity. Spent like 60 hours on it! Like many other RPGs the game starts with character creation
You get to pick your gender then you get pick your race. Here on the side you can see that the different races have different lore and
You get different attributes and who gives a shit. There's a race called Godlike.
I don't care what the other races get; this guy looks like he consumes the souls of the weak for a living
And this guy looks like he pays taxes on time. I also made him a merchant
And therefore I kind of had to make him a wizard, because let's be honest this guy is not going to be able to sell anything
without some serious magic
So you with this Caravan that are trying to get to the city and they are pretty close,
But then they have to stop in these somewhat dangerous ruins.
Something about a fallen tree and your character having a minor headache
So you're in these ruins and your caravan guy tells you to go out and pick some berries
Probably a bit annoyed, you know about the whole stopping the entire caravan thing
So you're picking berries, then you get to add stuff to your character's backstory and his dream
I decided my character used to own a store and his dream is to become filthy rich
You weren't actually allowed to pick what kind of store you used to own, so I'm thinking rubber ducks
Obviously as the story goes on we will find out more about our character
For example my character is incredibly racist, no, impressively racist.
So back at caravan the guy with the actually important job has disappeared
so we go out to look for the guy, and he's dead, then everyone else is dead
Then you're in a cave, then you come out from the cave
and you see some people having a fun midnight party. Boom now you can communicate with souls, you become a watcher.
So what is a watcher really? Well, it's a person that can talk to people's ancestral light, basically... ehh...
You can talk to all those farmers you have in your family tree. So now you might be saying well, that sounds astonishingly...
Useless. I thought so too at first, but I saw as the game went on I can they came to realize that yes
Yes, it is, but also being a watcher allows to see dead people
Here is where we make a movie reference if I made movie references
So how did our fella actually become a watcher?
Does it have something to do with the guys that did the ritual and then it was an explosion and whatnot
I don't know. I mean it's possible
It's a major problem with games like these for us that
refuse to read, but now you might be thinking "You refuse to read, but the game is most text, what?"
well it's not entirely text
It's also voice acted but my headphones are broke.
I have no idea what's going on right now.
So far in all my reviews I've never talked about against graphics, and I won't start now, but I want to give you guys a professional tip.
When I created my first character, I looked all around the place, I talked to everyone, I looked behind every corner
I just searched and searched and explored and travelled.
It took me 15 hours to make it to Act 2. So what have I learned from all that? Exploring is for idiots.
So I immediately created a new character
but this time I wasn't going to explore at all and it took me something like
40 minutes to get the second act. Just way superior! On your way there you will get a stronghold
it's this games player housing.
You can invest in this stronghold and make it look better and make it safer and here comes my second professional tip
don't.
First of all look at where it's located. The fine space all the way over here and to be honest
it's not really close to anything so before you start investing you need to remember that
you will probably never be able to sell this house for anything close to market value.
And apparently no one in the entire Eastern Reach has decided to invest in public transport. So what I'm saying is
Sell it immediately
Try to get a nicer place. Maybe a small house closer to Defiance Bay
Because investing money in the stronghold will just be a money thing [and] could just be a waste of time
You will never get it back... or maybe turn it into a brothel!
This game does not fill the brothel quota; then again there might be more brothels
but I just missed them because you know exploring is for idiots.
The game has three major problems that I can only describe as
super immersion breaking. First of all it's not very realistic: yes, the dragons and the magic and all that, yes those things aren't very realistic
But that's not what I'm talking about here. There was something else that was just weird.
Super minor spoiler here, when you first traveled the village Gilded Vale you see a tree and a bunch of people hanging out, heh, heh.
They were put there by this Lord Raedric guy, and you kind of get that yeah
He's he seems like a bit of a prick
But you know there's no pollution in the city or something like that so his environmental policies are probably fantastic
I'm thinking that's how he got elected
But anyways after you kill a couple of mushrooms and settle a bar fight, a guy will walk up to you and say
"Hey man so people are having it pretty bad here
you should like, I don't know, walk up and kill that Raedric guy." Obviously your answer is no because that would be mental.
You just solved a bar fight you're not really fit for storming a castle, are you. So obviously that's bloody unrealistic
I mean if you're at the store, and two people are arguing about return policy, and you're like
"Hey, can't we all just get along?" and then some guy walks up to you and says
"Hey man, I mean people are arguing about return policies. It's, it's not very KILL THE PRIME MINISTER"
You would be like "No, what are you talking about? No."
The second problem? Well these are the factions
I have found and you're able to join many of them, but there's one faction missing, do you see it?
I mean if you were if you are a hardcore fantasy fan like me you would like to see it immediately.
That's right, there's no communist faction. Obsidian [Entertainment] gotta put a city called Leningrad over here, and we could just walk there
And then you know, join them. You know, just have fun, have fun with the communists.
I mean lore-wise it makes a lot of sense. We're going to storm Gilded Vale and take over everything around it
Then lay siege to Defiance Bay, then storm the palace! The rulers are dead and Derwood is Red!
So anyways that would probably make a bit more interesting quest
While the crucible [nights] to have a quest for you pretty much have to go and get a Christmas gift or something I wasn't
Really paying attention, but you know it fits with it with with the fantasy setting exploring is for idiots [a] little problem. I faced
I'm sure it would happen to a lot of you, too
is that I got bored of leveling and
Collecting gold so I did what any sane person [would] do I went on bing and I searched for some sheets. [I] found this a
Nice-looking medallion website and I downloaded a file called pillars of eternity gold and Xp xI dot exe
Didn't work at all
Completely destroyed my computer
So that's order massive negative point hopefully in the future obsidian will patch this well to end it all
last month I [made] the Dragon age inquisition review I
Seriously think that the developers should have watched that before making this game if you're interested in Pillars of eternity
You should probably check out another review, and that's the kilian experience
Well, you could like and subscribe. I guess meeting caesar salad now last week. I was in Greek salad
But now trying something different, and I don't get the high
Then again, I might just be shit at making Caesar salad and just amazing at Making Greek salad
but anyways [uh] subscribe for more garbage uh
site